So good news is there is a page,
so there's documentation this time.
And this was created on the back of just
quite a lot of back and forth that we've
had in the last five years of
integrations.
And part of that back and forth is not
having standards,
not having it documented.
And then not being clear about the role
of the platform as well across all the
different teams. So as a recap, Ali,
if you recall last session,
we talked about the platform really
having two roles, right?
The first one is managing the core
services and then optimally distributing
those.
And the other one is providing a platform
for integration. So
we can onboard all sorts of apps if we
choose to bring it onto the ecosystem,
right? So that's where we started.
That's really what the first half of this
says.
But there are also a few things we want
to think about when we put together
platform integration requirements.
I think we talked about last time.
We're not here to solve all the usability
issues in the world. We can't,
especially if you look at, you know,
the app ecosystem that we have.
We have in-house tools,
we have development partner tools,
we have buy it off the shelf tools.
And as we grow,
there's probably going to be more and
more of those third party, you know,
sort of all-in-one solutions where we're
acquiring that solution and bringing it
into the platform.
Imagine if we had our standards applied
for how we build a core service.
So it needs to live in a container in a
certain way, it needs to be,
remember the micro front end discussion
we had,
it needs to be kind of decoupled and
ripped apart in a certain way.
Imagine having like 50 of those
conversations with 50 vendors.
That is just not realistic for us to do.
And the ROI is not there, right?
Because a lot of the stuff that we
acquired typically is not kind of tightly
coupled to the core. If it's core,
we would probably take more control over
it.
And in which case,
we would probably have a development
partner to build that stuff for us.
But as we get kind of broader into the
creases of the world, right? Like,
we're not ripping creases apart. Like,
that's just a standalone thing that we
provision access to for clients.
And we're going to call it a day. Now, if.
..
the relationship gets more robust and we
get client feedback about maybe certain
inefficiencies that they don't love and
those happen to be very important clients
and they want that solution to work more
cohesively with some of our core
functions,
then we would probably engage in a
different discussion,
probably through a statement of work or
through
changing the nature of the contract with
that partner and say, okay,
now we need maybe to invest a little bit
more on the seamlessness of the
interactions, which is more integration,
right?
So our starting point would never be,
let's go all out.
There'd be very limited cases for a fully
embedded app or like ripping an app apart
so we can put it in however we like.
We would just do that because the use
cases for that or the the the kind of the
ROI and the investment that would be
pretty low, right, at least to start.
So I kind of set that on this page here
and then we can dive into what do we
actually mean by integration.
So few principles, like, you know,
we got to treat the portal as a as a
launcher, right,
as opposed to you're really launching
apps off the portal. You're not trying to.
control absolutely everything in all the
apps within the portal itself.
So there are some pieces that we
centralize and then there's some pieces
that we federate or even decentralize
when it comes to control.
So like things like authentication,
feature access, data access, okay,
like you should have one profile for that
as a user and that profile should kind of
carry with you.
no matter what app you get into,
whether it's a core app like trading,
if you have a set of R codes, okay,
you should probably be only able to trade
on those R codes.
Or even if you're in a third party app,
you're still working on set of accounts.
So chances are you want a global
definition of what R codes a user has,
and then that gets passed into all the
systems so that the data access is
consistent.
right? But same thing with firm context,
user context. If you're a French speaker,
ideally you go into the other apps, okay,
you see it in French too,
because your language setting is French
on compass, right?
So there's certain things that we say,
okay,
it makes sense for us to have compass as
the source of truth and the definition
for it.
But there are just some other things that
don't make any sense.
And a good example of that is like
session synchronization.
So for session management, for instance,
on Compass, we have a 15 minute expiry.
It's a security thing.
Maybe we entertain extending that at some
point. But today,
each app comes with their own session
management policies, right?
Are we going to go through the hassle and
the investment of developing that session
synchronization mechanism for these 50
apps? The answer is no, because again,
ROI is low. Okay,
if you're kind of spinning off and SSOing
into an app, you work on the app,
compass times out,
is it the end of the world? No,
people just go back and log back in,
right?
Same thing with like session expiring,
rerouting, you know,
core applications always reroute you to
the compass landing page.
Do you really need to do that? Again,
you're now negotiating with 50 apps,
even some of our internal teams are bank
apps, right?
You're trying to negotiate work to get
that rerouted to the compass landing page.
We're just not going to do that, right?
Because actually we tried.
And then we failed because it's
impossible to prioritize those things.
And in some cases,
there's technical constraints.
And then there's, again,
it comes down to the money.
There's investment.
We don't want to do that. So, so when we,
when we take a look at the concept of
what the kind of the role of the portal
of the compass kind of platform does,
it's really that.
kind of enforcing consistency and
centralization of some things,
the things that make sense to us,
the things that matter,
which mostly is around access and like,
you know,
authentication and authorization.
You got to keep that consistent,
as well as just the global hierarchy of
information that gets presented, right?
Because people ultimately have to find
**** on the platform.
A secondary role, we, you know,
we could entertain selective application
of some of these standards,
depending on what it is,
and it really depends on the situation.
We looked at, I mean,
Soma is probably not a good example,
but Infinite Tools, for instance,
what is was a good example of when we
when we first started off,
because of all sorts of reasons.
that we can probably talk about another
time, we kind of said those tools,
it's really not super critical to get
them embedded into the core experience.
They are reference tools.
They are data tools.
People go to those tools to look up
information about something.
It's inefficient for a user,
but compared to time to market of getting
those tools launched and getting them
into the hands of users,
versus doing kind of putting in the
effort to do the integration work with
Infinite the way we wanted to. Again,
the ROI just wasn't there at the time,
knowing that at some point it will become
more relevant because when we launched
with Infinite,
there were 10 tools and now there is 20
and we're going to add more over the
course of the next few quarters.
And so we kind of said.
okay, now is the time, right?
Maybe we don't put a simple SSO with a
site nav and all these tools are
contained elsewhere.
We're going to at least do a routing
integration and make sure that it appears
in the correct place in the information
architecture.
So things can kind of change,
but maybe that's an example of like,
we're going to be selecting.
about the type of integration that we
apply depending on what the app is and
depending on what it does at the time.
And that function might change and then
we might come back and say, okay, well,
I think now is the time to bring it
closer to the ecosystem.
And so that I think the second part
summarizes as well. I just kind of maybe.
Yeah,
I think I provided a recommendation here
to say that there's so many ways. Oh,
sorry. Yeah. Sorry, I have a question.
I think with Infinite,
we have a two-way integration.
They integrate,
somehow they are using our features and
packages.
And also what you're saying,
we also are trying or try to onboard
their internal tools within our platform
to expose it to other firms or other
things.
Based on this,
I want to know that when we say we
integrate our tools from visual
standpoint, what does it mean?
It means we get their API and we build
something customized over those APIs.
Or not, we good question. Yeah,
when we talk about platform, yeah,
when we talk about platform integration,
we're talking about app-level integration,
so UI integration, right?
So we're not looking at, ohh, you know,
Infinite has like the market data APIs
for getting like the equity board
information. We're not saying that.
You give us the APIs and we build the
front end,
'cause then that is just Compass building
in front end, right? This specific, like,
I guess tiering of integration talks
about if Infin actually built the full
app front to back,
how do I bring that whole app into the
Compass platform? Yeah, so, so yeah, like.
..
We can kind of get into the types of
integration, but yeah, visually,
we're really talking about how do I get
access to that app?
How do I get a client to access that app?
Do I give them access through Compass?
Do I not?
Because we have situations where they
don't even come through Compass.
You heard the discussion about external
systems, right?
Do I give them access through Compass?
And then when I land in that app,
it kind of looks like all the other apps
in Compass.
Do I give him an access compass? It,
I get access, like you know,
the user gets access one,
but it opens in another tab. Yeah,
here you, there you go. Yeah, sorry,
my my question was early. OK, no, no, no,
it's a good, yeah, 'cause we're gonna,
yes, good train of thought,
but maybe maybe to just kind of talk
about what this part means.
selective and progressive integrations,
what I just explained is,
you don't go down the path of,
let's build a, let's do a three month,
five month,
six month project to do an integrated
module, talk about module federation and,
you know,
decoupling an app into micro front ends
and all that crazy ****,
because that takes time for a new vendor
to do that.
More often than not,
you're not going to commit down that path
because number one,
if you're working with a new vendor,
you don't know that relationship is going
to go well or not.
You're going to do this,
you're going to spend all this money
investing in a project to, you know,
to get certain parts of what a vendor
builds tightly integrated into Compass.
Well,
you probably want to prove that the
functionality has value first.
and that the relationship is robust
enough that you bake it into the
ecosystem.
So rarely do we ever start to say for
something new,
especially for something that's bought
off the shelf,
we're going to do an integrated module.
More often is, okay,
maybe we direct people to it.
But over time, okay.
that again, that necessity might change,
right? We might want to say, okay, like,
well, this is a high use tool. Like,
it's often paired with, I mean,
people do trades,
they do this other thing.
And so we might have a conversation
because it's now impacting the
productivity of the firms,
because obviously the higher the
integration,
the more seamless the experience is going
to be,
so the more effective people are going to
be on the platform.
Maybe we maybe we invest more, right?
So typical, I guess,
within the product ecosystem,
we're going to see that looser
integration is typically where a majority
of the applications are brought onto the
platform. Maybe there's some stuff,
I'll talk from Tiering in a second,
I realize this came before this. Yeah,
yeah, I see.
Like the, you know,
structured being around kind of like the
optimization of the core services,
that stuff is very, very few.
You'll see that accounts and servicing
and trading is your on the platform to do
it.
That's pretty much the majority of the
stuff that we want to see together, right,
housed together,
and the stuff that impacts our user.
It.
Yeah, yeah.
I just put, yeah, OK.
So just general rule of thumb,
if you look at the product ecosystem,
you're going to see that actually a lot
of the integrations are going to be kind
of the lower,
more decoupled end of the spectrum.
It's easy for us to do. It gives,
it achieves a core objective of giving
people access to things without having to
long in multiple times.
And then as it gets...
You know,
as the need increases for for the
usability,
we're gonna we're gonna invest more,
so I'm gonna get into the tiering. So,
when we think about this is the attempt
to classify it,
not everything falls strictly into these
categories,
because this came after we've attempted
multiple integrations, so...
we can get into what doesn't conform to
these models later,
and we can inspect them one by one,
because each of them are kind of a little
bit funky today. But.
learning from that,
this is an attempt to say there are
certain approaches we want to take and
they should be consistent.
So that number one,
from a maintainability perspective, okay,
we know exactly how the apps integrated
and then it serves a very specific
objective depending on the type of
integration that you do.
So I kind of said there's four.
Four tiers, starting with...
the lightest version of an integration,
which is actually no integration at all.
We actually have those.
So your goal of having is tier 0
integration is we have a digital
ecosystem, we have product on the shelf,
not everything is discoverable through
the platform because we don't provide
URLs to it.
Again, Digit is a really good example.
Nobody would know it exists unless we
told them, right?
And even if they do know,
if clients do know that it exists because
they actually subscribe to Digit,
there's nowhere for them to find it.
They just have to know that there's this
URL that gets them access to Digit, right?
You're not going to go through Compass,
you're not.
going to find that. So to kind of,
you know,
to improve the discoverability of the
features that firms have subscribed to,
we say, well, if we don't,
if we're not concerned about multiple
logins,
at least we can host this concept of
providing links on the platform so that
it's basically an inventory of stuff that
people can have access to.
No integrations, URL only,
you would put that URL onto the platform
under the application section,
and then you click on the URL and it
tells you to sign in to whatever system
you choose to have.
Reason why we even might want to do that
really truly is just about like, yep,
you have access to this thing,
so here's the link, right?
So like Kris is a good example of that.
today. Actually, no,
we don't provide Kris on legacy because
we configure which environment the front
has. Not even on legacy.
Not even on legacy.
So very minimal cases here,
but if there is a conversation that need
to be had where it's like, okay,
what's the quickest way of distributing
URLs basically to systems,
we'd be looking at a tier zero.
Right, which is,
it's zero because it's not actually an
integration.
Um...
So use cases around that would be stuff
that's like, you know,
completely unrelated to the core.
Maybe it's very specific to certain users.
Maybe it's like we're not really clear
where this capability is going to land.
You know,
often you go out to search for things
that our firms are missing and you think,
oh,
I found this thing and I'm going to start.
marketing it to the users,
you don't actually know how many firms
are going to adopt. And until you know it,
is it really worth trying to go through
and negotiate an integration with that
vendor? Probably not.
So maybe for ease of discovery,
we allow a URL to appear on our platform.
And until the demand is established,
we kind of leave it like this and not try
to invest too much into even the SSO
portion of it.
There are apps that actually clients
really don't care about having a second
login. So that can qualify as well, right?
Things that are unrelated to your core
experience,
things that they're used to having
multiple logins because they have so many
tools in their own environment as well.
If the demand isn't clear around having
like a fragmentation of login experience,
you're also not going to invest in that
integration, right? Like firms are fine.
And if they're fine.
Who's for us to say,
let's put in the 250K to do an
integration for them?
You're probably better off working on
something else, right?
So there's that as well. Again,
like I think Kris is a really good
example that we had,
like maybe 2 firms ask us if they can SSO
into Kris,
but mainly for security reasons.
Well,
and then the final use case would be like,
yeah, if there's no access controls,
you don't really need to do anything. So,
like,
so there could be some maps that fall
into this category, not a whole ton,
but there could be.
And I would say those are typically the
reasons for it.
And then when you enter this scenario,
like the specificities, I guess,
of the platform role is it really acts as
a navigation hub only,
doesn't really do anything else.
right? It's cheap and cheerful, right?
That's about it.
But then we get into tier one,
which is our kind of like our heavy tier.
We're going to do a little bit more than
that. So for tier one integration,
the goal here is, well,
we got to do more than just the
navigation only because there's specific
reasons for it. Number one is again.
We have an app ecosystem.
We want people to have access to it when
they subscribe to it.
We want to provision.
We want to be able to get that assigned
to a user, track the usage of that app.
We also want to provide a seamless login
experience so that you're not going to
like the multiple login scenarios.
This would typically happen if it's a
heavily used app, right?
Like if people are going in every day,
every other day, okay,
you really don't want people logging in
twice.
and maintain a completely separate user
management lifecycle process for that app,
right?
So now we're starting to see operational
efficiencies and a better experience for
clients for some of the more heavily used
things that we know that they're kind of
going into every day or every week.
It's a better traceability for us,
better auditability, and if we need that.
especially on things like licensed
products,
we're going to want to start seeing that,
right?
Which means that that user management and
provisioning of that feature should
probably now be brought into the platform.
So this is now we start to see some of
that central management of some certain
things, which is feature access,
data access, and login authentication.
from the platform. Usually these are,
I would say, core,
core adjacent capabilities, right?
You can still technically kind of,
you don't have to make it all look the
same.
You would typically have something that's
maybe not like really tightly coupled to
the core,
have it launch in a separate tab and call
it a day. That's not a problem for users.
Then you would do a tier one integration
for that because tier one really gets you
just managing, remember, the access,
the authentication, right?
It's not an experience integration at
that stage.
You might have legacy tool where you know
what, the integration is not justified.
We have a lot of those.
Secure zones are a really good example.
All the secure zone apps,
there's nine of them.
You can't take them apart, right?
It is what it is.
So we got to take it just out-of-the-box
and deal with it.
We actually try to negotiate.
Better integration with some of these
apps, like GIC was a really good example,
it just didn't work.
We spent months and months and months
trying to figure out how they were going
to prioritize,
like even things like session expire,
rerouting back to us,
and then we found like a they had a like
they had to build net new stuff to
support that flow, and we're like, yeah,
you know what, it's just not worth it.
Remember that conversation?
GIC integration.
It was done backward.
It was done backwards, yeah. So, but, but,
like, you know,
as it relates to kind of core product
types,
does GIC need to be tracked alongside
your equities and mutual fund? No,
it does not. Like,
if there was a huge case where.
across all the product types,
I need a consolidated experience,
I need a consolidated dashboard,
I need everything in one place,
and you know,
all of our users tend to have like have
that requirement.
Then we would have fought a lot harder to
bump GIC into a tier 3 integration.
But GIC is a product that can just live
on the side. Really, anybody can trade it.
You don't have to be a trader to trade it.
It's just.
purchasing, like, you know, like,
you know, like basically deposits, right?
So it's an interest product. So we didn't,
like,
there was not a lot of harmonization that
was required,
even though we considered that a core.
And so we still decided, okay,
it's not worth the fight.
Let's put it as a tier one.
And let's make sure that at least your
compass profile.
enables you to trade or purchase GICs and
it will stop it there because that's
actually the most important part is we
want to be able to enforce that.
All right, so in this case,
platform role access more of a security
management tool, right?
It's a secure app launcher,
and on top of that, obviously,
it also directs navigation,
and it's minimal effort, I think,
for most, well, minimal effort.
as of now because we give clear
instructions and then if you don't count
the churn because people get confused,
it's minimal.
But there was a lot of churn before in
understanding what this tier means.
But there should be very little work for
that third party app to do.
It's because all the feature onboarding
stuff tends to land on our own team,
right?
So we take that on.
We can prioritize it ourselves.
We have full control over when we do that
integration.
Third party apps just needs to do a few
things to consume what we pass over to
them, which should be,
which should not be a lot of overhead and
typically you win those negotiations,
right, because of that,
that smaller scope.
Drawbacks,
you still don't have a good seamless user
experience. Obviously,
most SSOs send you to a new tab.
They're not kind of embedded in the core
platform experience.
There's typically no need to either.
You can go into the UI philosophy for
that,
UX philosophy for that in another time.
But there are certain limitations,
obviously, with this approach.
So if we want to do more,
so now we're getting into the territory
of,
in addition to kind of that centralized
security, if we want to do more than that,
now we're getting into the,
we're now optimizing for the experience
for the user.
And kind of when we get into a higher
tier, because I mean,
if you get into this space and, oh,
By the way, I want to mention,
we don't talk about data integration here
at all. That's a completely separate,
separate discussion.
This is really front-end app integration.
So when we want to bring the...
context of that app closer with your core
workflows,
now we got to start embedding stuff into
the platform. So tier 2 is about,
I guess tier 2 and tier 3 are really just
different ways that you can embed things
into the platform. I call it out as a,
I guess, a different tier B, just again,
just because of just the effort.
involved in doing it is still incremental.
But tier 2 for me, which I don't think,
I think we kind of like we have a,
we have a half baked version of this,
like servicing this,
I think kind of a half baked version of
this.
But the idea here is now we're trying to
contain the contents of the app within
the platform.
So if you're working on one thing in the
app and then you want to swivel and pivot
into the other thing and you need it to
kind of coexist.
Again,
very rare for a platform to need to do
this.
A good example would be if you're working
on an app and then in the platform
there's notifications or in the platform
there's like maybe like an FX conversion
tool or something. Well,
that tool universally applies across all
the apps.
If you're in the middle of an app that
does a transaction that requires FX,
ideally...
We don't send you to another place and
then you come back to this app to get the
platform tool to use the FX conversion
and then go back to do the thing. Ideally,
it kind of sits on top of each other,
right?
And so the only way to do that when you
have an external app is to literally pull
that app actually into our UI container.
And so tier 2 describes that process of
how do I...
you know, like, well,
iframe is probably the best example of a
tier 2, right? Like,
there's maybe a handful of different ways
to do it. But now,
if I want to kind of have that
side-by-side experience,
I need to bring the context of those two
different pieces of functionality
together.
When we need to do that and the demand is
high for that, then we say, okay,
at minimum, we should.
probably do a tier 2 integration,
if not a tier 3.
Difference though between a tier 2 and
three is we still try to not go too far
into starting to decompose that app,
right? We'll take the app as it is,
love them for who they are, and...
And, and,
and just try to nest them into the
appropriate place in the platform,
so that they can be independently
deployed. They can, you know,
we can still do all the things that we do
in tier one,
because the security context is already
established, right?
But then we also we also kind of do kind
of like runtime dependency management.
at that stage,
because you're iframing something.
So I go in and now I have to make the app
fail gracefully in a certain way if it
doesn't load, right?
Like the session synchronization now has
to take place.
You can't have an embedded app timeout in
the middle, in the platform,
like that would just make no sense.
So now we got to add those session
synchronization requirements in there.
And then obviously we got to control the
expiry, timeout, expiry,
all that needs to be synchronized.
So there's an incremental cost to doing
that, but it's still not, you know,
it's still not as like intense as let's
start decoupling everything.
So we don't have,
I don't even think we have use cases for
it today.
Like the only good example is servicing
because servicing is kind of like, yeah,
in the middle here somewhere, but not.
It was done weird,
so we can get into the nuances of why it
was done weird. Actually,
I'm not going to get into it.
I'm going to get Candi and Owen to tell
you what was done weird about it.
But ultimately,
we use this because it's still not hugely
costly,
but there's now you guys should manage
that external dependencies during kind of
deployment and runtime, right?
When you embed an iframe.
everything has to work.
You got to make sure that that tool
doesn't inherit too much from the
platform. So it breaks. Like we have Soma,
we have an issue where,
because we tried to do a tier 2 plus plus,
we started to build dependencies on the
app to restyle and all of that.
So when they do something,
it actually breaks our UI sometimes.
Right, that's not that's not great.
In this case,
the app is still self-contained.
We're just trying to embed it.
So drawbacks,
obviously more dependencies to manage,
right?
And then if you have problems with
accessibility consistency,
you're going to be able to know,
you're going to know, right? Like,
because accessibility is consistent in
the core platform.
Once you go outside of the app,
once you go outside of the core platform
and inherit an app,
it might not be the case,
and you're going to know as a user.
And then not every app comes with the
same responsive behaviors as a core
platform. So if you embed something,
it's going to start looking a little
weird. So really,
we don't want to do this because it
breaks the app experience,
it breaks the platform experience if it's
not done right.
I know in the 90s everybody loved iframes,
but it's not a good idea.
It's like you have to be very intentional
about it, right?
Okay,
final one and then we'll get into the
details of integration standards.
This is an overview. So yeah,
we really want to go to town,
then we're looking at a full micro app
integration, right?
We're going to bring pieces of an app
functionality into the core experience.
The goal here is we're going to make it
so seamless that you don't know what's a
different app so that you're productive.
and you're not kind of reorienting
yourself constantly.
This is a big thing with when you buy an
app,
you gotta learn a completely different UX,
right, for that user. Even things,
simple things like filter,
like how many apps have we gone through
where, okay,
all the apps are designed different,
there's no standard, and you go in,
it's like, how do I filter things again?
Like, it's gonna be different.
So there's value in drawing that UX
consistency alignment.
A tier 3 integration should do that
because once we start to say, okay,
your portfolio management system,
I want to put your analytics widget into
our platform and have it sit alongside
other dashboard widgets, right?
I'm now taking a component from you and
shoving it into the platform.
That thing probably shouldn't look
different to the next thing. It's like,
you know, a little market data charts.
It shouldn't look different because it's
a totally different orientation then.
And you're not quite sure at that point,
like,
what does this thing do and what is it
not do? Yeah, right.
That's the issue with UX inconsistencies.
And so when we kind of go down that path
and we really want to do it,
then we have a conversation about is it
worth it? Because this is now.
all about user productivity,
user experience efficiencies, and at BNI,
it's a B2B business,
that kind of requirement typically is a
little bit lower in our prioritization
mindset, but, you know,
clients do complain and they do become
inefficient and we don't want them to be
inefficient at the end of the day.
So at some point.
we have a discussion about do we do a
tier 3 integration with certain things
that are critical,
certain things are embedded in the core
workflow.
A good example actually that Stan's
trying to negotiate now is to have a Fun
Fact integration.
So Fun Fact is a secured zone tool.
It completely lives off to the side.
Anytime you buy a fund,
you have to send the fund.
information to the investor before or at
the time of buying that fund.
I think you can still kind of can't
remember POS 3 requirements,
like shortly after as well. I don't know.
It's A regulatory requirement.
Right now it's a separate app. So really,
truly,
you're in the core mutual fund flow.
You're trying to purchase a fund.
And then you have to remember,
Did I send, like,
has this investor bought the fund before?
Okay, it's not in your positions.
Now I got to go to Fun Facts,
this other tool.
I'm going to SSO into this secure zone
tool,
and then I'm going to pull up this
complete, like, it's a complete,
it's an ancient app. It looks terrible.
I'm going to figure out how do I add the
account and add the security I'm trying
to purchase,
and I'm going to try to send it out.
And then I track it there as well.
Have it, has it, you know,
have I sent it out before or not?
And what have I sent before to this to
this account, right?
And then I come back to here, okay,
I'm going to finish my trade, right?
That's a core,
that's a fundamental workflow that if a
client,
if one of our firms is assisting a client
in placing that investment,
they want to do it in 10 seconds or less.
Right,
because it really hinders your
productivity when you go, like,
you're just trying to buy a fund. Like,
why should it take you 5 minutes?
That's ridiculous.
You have a whole host of other orders to
process.
And so they're not meeting their
efficiency objectives as employees.
We're getting in their way because we
have this other app sitting in the ether
to the side that nobody's touched for 20
years, right?
And so Stan's now negotiating, okay,
I need that fun facts to be integrated
into my order ticket.
I need that component to be there so that
the fun facts can be managed or at least
can be initiated and sent at the time of
order entry if I can see that that
investor doesn't have that position,
right? So
That's what we get into.
Do we do we have a tier 3 discussion with
that team who's managing fun facts?
So he's actually going through that right
now.
And.
And with this integrated module,
like a premium,
when we say fun fact integrated into the
trade module.
It's going to get an information from
FontFact, is that right?
Or it's a like a transaction interaction
because it's different.
It's like the get API or post API.
Remember,
this is still app integration because I
think where we're actually going to land
with this is tier 3 is still too hard,
so we do an API integration.
Because that's a lot easier, right? Yeah,
yeah, yeah,
but fun fact doesn't provide API.
It seems that it doesn't,
so you'll have to integrate, okay, yeah,
the actual physical app in. So, like,
this is the like the debate we typically
have with Teams. It's, you know,
do we bring the app in,
or can you give us an API,
or can you even give us like batch data
so we can put it into a UI, 'cause it...
be a lot faster for us to go around the
issue than it is to try to negotiate the
right way to do it. And in each case,
each app is actually different because
it's managed by different teams,
like the internal ones. To some extent,
the vendors of the same,
but some vendors could be more difficult
than others, right? Yeah, actually.
Maybe something is cheaper in this middle
because fun fact is an internal
application.
I remember before inventing API,
we were actually exchanging a view of
database, you know? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You remember? Yeah, I think...
Instead of, you know,
integrating something like that,
I know that it's somehow obsolete, but no,
we're cheap and cheerful. Like, we,
you know,
you'll have a conversation with Ray about
the air quote integration that we have.
A lot of it is just files, right?
It's even cheaper than that. It's like,
give us a snapshot of the database in
some format.
I'm going to take it and put it in our
data platform.
and call it a day.
At least I can show the clients the
information that they need. Yeah. So yeah,
like it's, and it just depends, again,
even data integration,
it just depends on the demand, right?
Like there's tiering for that too,
is if things do need to be real time,
well,
there's narrow use cases of when things
need to be fully synchronized and in real
time.
Biggest use case we have is trading
because you need to have accurate,
just-in-time balances and position
information for you to execute something
in real time that will sell on the market
in real time.
So you need that real time information.
So that data, wherever you get it from,
you can't give me a file.
I got a read from the book of records.
Yeah, well, it's right,
even like a fifteen-minute lag is not a
not a you can't do that, right?
It's a you're trading like a trade a
minute, yeah.
Okay, any, so let me see,
what else am I gonna? So benefits,
it'll be the best experience ever, right?
Seamless composition, but drawbacks is,
it's a heavy investment, it is expensive.
And the most important part,
because we never, the reason,
there's a reason why we never did this
right is
the engineering maturity on either side.
So do they even know how to do this?
A lot of times our teams don't, right?
So when you take,
can you give me a microfund or micro app,
the other team might not know what you're
talking about. Okay.
Never mind managing independent
deployment, right?
And runtime integration,
like they don't know how to do that stuff.
So that has to be kind of part of our
assessment and recommendation when we
kind of toss to the teams and say, okay,
I know we want to do a tier 3,
but I'm looking at that team,
they can't pull it off.
So why don't we start with the tier one
and kind of go from there. And this is,
I think,
this is the standalone content that.
you have provided and it's not being
mapped or addressed by JP or Esther.
It's what's your idea and your framework,
and it's not being converted into a
technical work. Yeah, they still have to,
I would say there's, like,
they kind of get it because these are our
requirements to them. Yeah, requirements,
but still the...
They have done it use case by use case.
They have not gone to a framework.
You know, you have a framework,
but on the engineering side,
it's not a framework.
It's use case by use case.
It is because I like this page, I think,
was created a month ago. Okay.
Before you joined. I was like, oh,
I better put this together. Yeah, okay.
Yeah, so no, we never, you're right,
it's case by case.
That's why the implementations are so
weird, right? It's because one,
like we actually never gave consistent
requirements.
And then on the back of not giving
consistent requirements,
like every single project,
we end up like handing,
I end up showing up and negotiating with
them to say, no, we gotta do this, no,
we can't do that. And then.
team comes back,
well the feasibility is not there,
we can't do this and then.
You know, yeah,
so it it's an opportunity to standardize
that the technical side with them. OK,
that's what it is not not been done.
I have one, actually, one more question.
It's more fundamental. Yeah,
if we look at from...
Maslow pyramid, you know,
because we move from bottom to the top.
Except, you know,
let's put the technical things aside.
I want to start from Firm 360,
where the journey starts. For example,
when one firm has subscribed to Soma.
and we want to deliver it.
And now they have to do it into a
disintegrated way to have separate
credential and go there login and things.
The thing is that
If ROI justifies and if the business,
for example, from top manager says, no,
they don't, for this specific client,
they don't like this user experience.
They say we want to bring a more unified.
And we have to go through this user
journey to make it EMPLF. OK.
I want to understand what's the scale of
the cost and ROI, how we calculate,
how the user, how the,
how the actually the requirements, I mean,
business requirement gets initiated and
then comes to you and then down to the
road.
to the engineering and delivery, you know?
Well, it's I guess there's a,
it's a very simple,
it's a very simple process,
which is Ray and I,
Pat and I kind of chat about it and we
say, usually typically say,
do we really need to do that? If not,
then we're going to start here.
That's how it works. Backed by, so,
you know,
we have that conversation and then I
would kind of ask the team, like, guys,
like, what's the feedback?
If it's a new product,
there's no feedback.
If there's like an existing product,
we get feedback.
So we would have the conversation about
do we have experience frictions there?
Is it is it kind of high on the list over?
major firms.
Our typical list for major firms have a
lot of stuff in core and not so much in
integrations. And so, like,
there's you look at the feedback,
you look at the cost to implement,
you look at other priorities that you
have. Obviously,
it's always relative to other priorities
as well.
Most of our third party integrations
Like the ROI on a tier 3 is so low
compared to a multi-firm.
That's why you see in the backlog still,
there's a whole bunch of like SSOs that
are lined up and we never get to them.
Because there's always a higher order
prize and we say until something like a
digit gets to, you know, like 50, 60,
70% adoption across all of our firms,
is it really even worth it to start that
conversation?
with them versus multi-firm.
Multi-firm tends to always win because we
haven't done it yet.
And that affects all users,
even though the cost is like a five to
six month effort,
so talking about like 500K,
like that's the investment,
but it eliminates operational processes.
It eliminates, like on our side,
eliminates processes on the firm side.
eliminates the multi-user ID,
it does eliminate the data privacy risk.
So the benefit case of that stacks up
quite a lot high,
even if you don't do a quantitative,
strict quantitative approach to it.
That list right there is okay,
like who cares about the digit SSO, right,
compared to that.
Once you solve that though,
and that problem goes away, okay,
what's next on the list?
then that relative prioritize,
like that relative priority might change,
right? We might go, okay, well, you know,
I think it's,
is it half or 1/4 from juice creases?
Do you remember?
It's a pretty big,
I think it's a pretty big number.
You look at all the integrations and
again,
like whether it's a security perspective
or firms are saying like this thing,
like managing multiple logins is not good,
then we would say, okay,
which of our most important firms are
really complaining about and is that
consistent? If it is, then okay,
let's bring that up for discussion and
then let's have the conversation about,
okay, we do this with Kris.
The cost is 200k,
is it worth it or can we save somewhere
else or can we add value somewhere else?
It's not a science. It's like,
a lot of it up to this point is pretty
intuitive to say,
do we even want to go down that process
of quantifying it? No,
it's pretty obvious.
When it becomes less obvious,
I think that's when you want to provide
evidence.
Which would be like after multi-firm,
it starts to get tricky.
You're gonna have to start quantifying
stuff.
And then we usually like, we like budget,
budget friendly versions of anything
anyway,
so it always starts here no matter what.
Okay. Yeah. Like servicing, we,
we probably like for me,
like I wouldn't have gone down that path
of what we did now,
knowing how much it cost of us, it was.
I see, how many months? 9-11?
Yeah.
Yeah, it was it was horrible.
It sounds like a long time.
It was a late time ago, yeah.
It sounds like your just for people to
understand what servicing was.
And why,
why we needed it in the in the in the
platform,
and then you know they built it on React
and we're on Angular,
and then so there were incompatibilities
there.
So that was not,
that cost was not justified.
So from another perspective,
I understand that Compass X is an asset
or national bank, OK?
So people or firms or clients are using
it, OK?
Now, there are two ways to look at it.
Whether it works as a third party like
courses, to say, okay, it works,
I integrate to Compass X to scale up,
to add more revenue for myself.
because I have integrated into Compass X,
I advertise,
and they have a great marketplace.
They advertise me and they upsell me to,
you know, to other parties.
Or it's in another way that Compass Safe,
Compass X says,
I am a junior marketplace and I am
looking forward to integrating as many as
possible,
as many as good third-party apps to make
myself reputable, to
get more market share.
I want to understand right now, today,
what is our position in the market and
what is our weight in the market and
which way or which Rd.
are we going or it's kind of like
combined.
Yeah,
it's maybe it's actually somewhere in the
middle because like we don't do,
we don't go out and we're not at the
stage where we're proactively doing
market scanning and finding that new
opportunities.
We're not in that position yet.
All of these are based on client demand.
to date,
and we haven't even addressed that, right?
So our clients use third party tools,
a lot of them use similar tools,
like whether it's a CRM or financial
planning,
they go out and procure it on their own.
And so I think it was a few years ago,
well, when we started the AGM,
when we started the,
this just kind of this new ecosystem
strategy.
All we did was we actually just took a
look at across all of our firms and say,
what are the, what is everybody using?
And can I get a bit better deal for them?
That's how it started. So it's not,
we don't use the app marketplace like
most marketplaces do.
We don't need to advertise ourselves in
that way.
We don't need to say we have a robust,
best-in-class ecosystem. Like,
when people come through our door and
we're prospecting,
we have that one-on-one conversation
instead. And, you know,
those who kind of have multiple
custodians through word of mouth,
they also kind of say, oh,
is BNI better or worse?
They kind of people hear about it in that
way.
Um...
I would say, yeah,
I would say that position has changed as
well.
We needed to do a little bit more
marketing seven years ago,
so we did talk about the platform
ecosystem.
We said this is a thing that we're going
to have, and it's going to be your,
you know,
it's going to be your technology platform
of choice. I think we've gotten there now.
Our clients are saying, like,
whenever we do like kind of like our
pitches and demos, like they're saying.
good things about it, like, oh yeah,
this platform is there.
So I think that need to kind of establish
this,
like that reputation as a as a FIN tech
provider is not as high as you would
think for,
at least compared to other wealth tech
startups, right? Like, as a, you know,
if you're if you're pure tech, yeah,
you gotta do a lot of work because you
gotta sell them to these institutions,
right? We have.
a pretty good position in the sense of we
have majority of market share,
people know if they want to go
independent and they're big.
Chances are NBN is probably the only
custodian that can support you because we
have enough of our portfolio of services
to be able to deal with anything and the
operational expertise and technology
comes with that. So that's really the...
the poll and not this.
This is more so much,
can we just save you some costs, right?
Like as we kind of go through and we find
that we, again,
because we have 70% of the market share,
when we go on to negotiate,
it's going to be way better than you as
an independent firm trying to acquire a
license or something.
Right? And then it's in some cases,
even the bank, National Bank, right?
Like it's not just sometimes NBI goes and
negotiates, right?
Because there's specific tools our
independent network wants,
but then there's just some tools so
generic that like our bank will negotiate
a MSA for it and then we take licenses
from the bank.
Bank is even more negotiating power in
that process, right? So something like a
Salesforce and BNI is not going to be
able to negotiate a Salesforce deal.
National Bank will negotiate the
Salesforce deal, right?
And so that we leverage for sure.
And our firms know that, you know,
they come to us because we're, you know,
part of this bigger thing.
There's disability,
there's economies of scale,
like all of that is a benefit from
working with National Bank.
And that's how we would position it to
the clients as well. Yeah,
so it's not definitely not case two,
more case one,
but then driven by driven by what we see
our clients do.
I would say maybe at some point you start
shoving technology down their throats,
but not not now.
The.
Any questions, any questions so far?
Is this making sense? Yeah, no,
what does JSC6?
Did I put an example? Is there?
So the last four others, the last one?
That's not GICs.
GIC is not a quarter, right?
It's not equity or mutual funds.
It is a navigation, so it's zero.
No one.
It's A1 mean, yeah.
I think it was the GIC was the closest to
this, like we had this conversation, yeah,
with the GIC team.
It was as close as we got to the standard.
Yeah.
Okay,
I was not expecting to spend this much
time on integrations,
but I do realize there's a lot of detail.
Okay.
So,
we talk about the goals and needs and
benefits and drawbacks. Very welcome.
Sorry,
I thought it was a crash for a little bit.
No, it's cool. You're taking,
you're taking shifts between you and I'll
fly on the wall though. Well, you,
you've already kind of got,
we're doing platform integrations. OK,
you've already gone through this with me
before, so...
Wanna save yourself some time?
We're gonna go into the meat of it.
In more detail, but we just started, so,
so purpose is up here, right?
What the role of the platform is,
use cases for the different integration
types, so context setting at the bottom,
like, so from this point onwards,
now we start to look into the actual
expectations that we do for.
each tier of integration itself.
It's bundled into some core standards
around capabilities, right?
So what's the scope?
What do we do when it comes to feature
onboarding, the INITIUM integration,
the experience integration,
of which there's a few things,
and then platform services integration.
Ali, again,
you realize that we don't talk about data
integration or API integration here.
That's a whole separate
That's a conversation with Ray, actually,
timing.
So just focus on how do I bring an app
into the platform. There are cases,
actually,
as we talk about app integration tiers
from zero to three.
There might be a decision to say API
integration is the easiest way to go,
in which case we don't talk about this at
all, right?
We don't talk about app integration at
all.
Again,
fun facts might be one of those where
it's like, okay,
maybe it's a nice little trigger to some
app endpoint that's made available.
We don't have to bring the app in at all
into the order ticket because I don't
know if real estate works out for it
anyway.
So we might have that discussion with
that fun facts team.
Okay,
so maybe I'll just kind of kind of go
through one tier at a time and talk about
the journey there, because we start with,
well,
what is the actual scope of what we need
to do? And again,
these are this is requirements context.
We don't talk about solutions here.
To your point,
we not actually establish the technical
implementation standards.
because I put this page together a month
ago and I shared it with you and that's
as far as I got.
And so when we talk to the technical
teams, for the most part,
if we articulate in this way,
they'll understand what to do.
But is it like,
do they do it consistently?
It still needs validation.
Because I'm not sure that they do.
And we might have to say,
actually use this example,
what we did for VRCs.
do it this way,
or what we did for like infinite,
don't do it that way,
because that's a very bespoke path,
like we have to tell them that still.
But it would be great at some point if
they can kind of establish the standards
as well on their side.
Okay,
so we'll do a quick pass on navigation
only because it's a really strong word.
Navigation only we talk about is just
posting the URL so people know that this
thing exists. Common. Right,
and so we're gonna, we're gonna, you know,
we're gonna list that as a feature
through our feature registration process
and we make a navigation update.
So feature onboarding is really simple.
You still have to represent anything that
appears on the platform that we want to
control as a resource.
So we have to register that resource.
Remember, we'll get into that later.
So we'll map that to the feature registry
so we can show or hide it for firms and
show or hide it for certain user profiles.
With the feature.
package assignment, like I said,
there's kind of two options here.
Do we allow the election for a firm or
not? We try to define that up front.
So if it's URL that should show up for
everybody, we say it's mandatory,
just give it to everybody,
or we can opt to control it.
And that's just kind of that ends our
feature onboarding discussion.
Two decision points, and we're done.
Nothing else exists, as you can see.
There is a decision point as well around
notifications. Do we want to send out?
Do we want to send out like any kind of
like outage communications or anything
like that? If so,
then we need to configure that in the
platform as well. And again,
that's a conversation that we can have,
right?
And that's pretty much it because it's a
link, right?
When we get into tier one though,
things we actually try to layer in
requirements at this stage, right?
Because it does need to talk to our auth.
We said.
Tier one,
the role of the platform changes where
they kind of the central security
management of it that needs to be
consistent because it's important that a
user logs in and they do have access to
what they need across the app ecosystem.
And so whether it's data access,
feature access, we want to normalize that.
And so we look to Compass to provide that
context. So
What we do? Well,
you still need to do the feature
registration and navigation updates,
but now I need to add the auth
integration right into it.
I need to make sure that the full kind of
firm user management lifecycle functions
that you saw,
like sort of the end-to-end journey of
like kind of provisioning the security
and provisioning access works.
And then we want to maybe consider,
but like I said, selective integration,
right? Depending on what the app is.
We want to consider, not always,
do we want to pass any firm specific or
user specific context to that app?
Really contingent on what that app is.
If it's a basic function that's kind of
sitting off to the side, why do we care,
right? But if it's a...
like a core adjacent thing where there's
a lot of information for you to present
it. Okay,
maybe we pass the language context over.
Because now, like,
maybe people want to see things in French
in both places,
already coming from the platform,
and you're trying to digest a bunch of
information.
So minimal,
I would say minimal is whatever is
required. And then at this point,
because we're going to enable that SSO,
basically this is the SSO solution, right?
We want to just make sure that that app
does not have, like has some mechanism,
like security protection mechanisms.
We don't have to manage that.
in the platform,
but at least we want to say you probably
should expire your session,
especially if your app is transactional
from a security perspective,
and match our standards for that session
expiry.
Like terminate the session when there's
an activity, right, at a minimum.
And then ideally,
either redirect to a Compass login page,
or if it's not possible, at least just.
kind of create a dead end so that people
know, okay, if I were to access it again,
I have to come back to Compass and log in
again and SSO back into it.
So the work that needs to be done as a
result is still,
I'm just going to make sure that the
feature is registered,
the resources are available.
And then this is where,
because we're fully onboarding that
feature onto the platform and applying
controls over it, remember all the.
packaging that we talked about last week,
Ali, the firm and user packaging,
whether it's core or non-core,
if it's core,
you gotta make sure it fits in the matrix.
If it's non-core,
add it to all the packages, right?
We need to make that determination now
because we're trying to access control
that application for the firm and for the
user, right?
So we do a little bit more on feature
package assignment.
To firms and users,
and then we do a little bit more,
obviously,
'cause the core of this tier of
integration is provisioning the SSO,
so that the app takes our context for
authentication and authorization, right?
So, at minimum,
when we do the kind of do the SSO,
you create an Okta token, Okta.
sends the token over to the app,
that digests that token and interprets it
and does whatever the app needs to do
with it.
And then.
I kind of put this in here,
but it doesn't always have to link is if
I were to, because again,
I'm provisioning the access,
I have a representation of access in the
Compass platform.
When I pass the user over to the app,
I should have auditability between how
the user is represented in the app if
it's different.
versus how it's represented in Compass,
right? I have to see that, okay,
I'm giving you access.
If it's a third party tool,
they typically have their own INITIUM
solution, right?
And then what we're doing is we're kind
of mapping. I have this access context.
I'm going to map it to their target
context.
I need auditability between the two.
So you'll see that in the secure zone
case, in the R2 case, we've.
physically put in the IDs to establish
that link,
because we have to as part of the
solution. Other times, we don't have to,
like infinite,
we don't store an infinite user ID or
whatever. That's a different integration.
But to the extent of kind of, I guess,
having end-to-end kind of centralized
management from Compass,
we just want to make sure that's
reconcilable.
in some way, shape, or form. And again,
there's degrees of how we want to do that
based on the feasibility and based on
what that target solution looks like.
This is a solution implementation detail.
Again,
that's why that technical team should
probably at some point standardize what
they do.
So again, like we get into authentication,
again,
context is going to be in the token.
You got to pass it on so that, again, I,
you know, I fulfill the job of compass,
which is I tell the app what this user
should have.
I don't allow the app to interpret that.
I'm like, here's the profile,
do something with that profile because it
should have information for this to this.
Um...
Session session management, you know,
like we're not remember this is a cheap
and cheerful way to give people unified
access and for us to have that kind of
lifecycle management of the app.
It's cheap and cheerful. So again,
we're not going to go full blown session
kind of management.
Session synchronization costs a lot of
money.
So we're saying just match the standard
but independent implementation.
of the on the app side,
just do the 15 minute expiry,
do the timeout, do the dead end, right?
Maybe if you're nice about it,
maybe remind the user when they're about
to time out, but not a hard requirement.
Penny, can I go back to authorization?
Yeah, so in specific like...
how we pass on the authorization from
campus to IS or to GIC is by the resource.
So resource is not just for the feature
control, but also for authorization.
And currently,
because I got asked this question a lot,
like in IS,
how do they know what feature to
provide or which tool the user has access
to, if there's a difference,
is by the resources assigned to the user.
So each one of them would represent
something.
And in the case for PayPal below,
is one feature.
But then there's different tiers.
So someone can view paper upload only,
someone can submit a paper application.
And those in campus,
based on which user role you're assigned
to, you will be assigned different user,
different resources.
And those are the resources that would
mean something.
When they render the apps in the target
application or target platform,
so they they don't couple too much to
what we call the user packages or user
group,
but they just need to fetch the resources
from us to do that authorization,
so I mean.
Yeah.
And,
and that package resources which we have,
I think it's a standard between us and
our, for example,
security zone applications,
because if it's not a standard,
how would they understand to map?
those resources into their application.
I believe, for example.
So, here is an exception. I mean,
I mean that, for example,
admin all or what account opening
underline, for example,
view whatever that resources that we
define in our packages is derived from
somewhere.
Okay, for example,
for from an insider application insights
secure zone,
because from what you are saying,
we are passing it to to that specific
application and secure zone,
so they need to understand that how it
comes and how to map it.
Is that alright?
I should qualify what I just said: the
resources applied to infinite apps,
and specifically talk about, yeah,
but the implementation standard is not
there.
It's like this is like our desired
requirement,
and there's like three different ways to
do it. OK,
like the infinite way is different from
the secured zone way,
and secured zone way we actually don't.
past anything because we said Compass
controls that access.
So if you don't get the access from
Compass, you can't get in anyway.
Because it's an SSO, right?
So I'm going to shut the URL off and I'm
not going to assign it to your profile.
You don't get that resource on the
Compass side.
Secure Zone never needs to know this
concept of resources.
They just need to know a user ID.
and how that user ID is defined in Secure
Zone itself,
because Secure Zone has its own access
control model. So in Secure Zone,
we're going to set up the user,
we're going to link it to a compass
profile,
we're going to define all the function
codes that defines the coarse grain
access that it has and the RR access,
and then at the point of SSO,
that passing of context.
will not include some of the stuff we
talked about because it doesn't need it
because it's defined on the secure zone
side. So technically we can,
we do not control access in secure zone.
We only validate whether or not you have
access to the feature and we provide the
link. What is a dip link or something?
So you click on, you go to GIC.
And then depends on your security profile
setup in the JSC application,
which function group code you have,
maybe you have given access, yeah,
between you and Lee.
So it click on the same link,
but then whatever user package you assign
in the compass world doesn't matter. Well,
it it.
Yeah, we manage it operationally, right?
So when somebody says,
I need to view GICs, okay, SAA team,
you better set up the view version of
GICs for this user in the secured zone
side.
So it's like the profile matches what's
defined on the compass side.
So this is actually good homework for you,
Ali.
Maybe you can go through all of our
integrations and document how it's done,
and then you can start to see like just
the different ways we've approached it in
the past and start to kind of standardize
it. Yeah.
And the biggest and the biggest risk
there, right,
is that there's no upward growth.
Oh, I can't say the word.
There's no STP to SAA.
So the biggest issue is you go to
competency, say,
give me view only and add this RR code to
my profile.
And if I have an existing profile called
Norris RA and you pass that over and no
one added the RR code or no one added,
I'm pooched. Yeah, yeah,
that's the problem today. That's why.
That's why we have a dedicated person
trying to clean this all up,
and he's been working on this for like 3
months now. So, like,
'cause it is a separate, like,
because it's manual in the back end,
so you have to request it,
and then you have to have a processor
actually physically update that secure
zone profile,
and if that guy does it wrong.
Then, who cares what game punk pump is,
basically? Yeah, that's why, like,
that's why in UAM,
this is why we kind of like, you know,
as a as a stretch goal or or nice to have,
like in the UAM I showed you yesterday,
there is that provisioning plan that
we've added,
so it's explicit instructions to the SA
team to get around the issue of no.
integration, right?
Sort of like access provisioning
integration is okay.
If we don't have that,
at least maybe I give you a very specific
set of instructions for system one,
very specific instructions for system 2.
Today, they just have to figure it out.
We give them a form and go, oh, okay,
yeah, I have to update your code here.
Sometimes they forget,
sometimes it's a copy and paste error,
sometimes their firms are not clear.
Sometimes it's not clear,
is it gonna be a secure zone app or not?
No,
here is a secure zone instructions that
you need to operate on,
and these are the R codes you need to
copy into there.
Let's make it a little bit more clear,
but this, but it's still offline,
still offline until such time as there's
a need, or you know,
there's a there's a gap capability.
Sorry, or they build a capability,
'cause we can't even, yeah, well,
I think they kind of, they kind of,
they kind of are almost there, yeah,
but it's also like the, yeah,
this is the prioritization,
that's the issue, sure.
And to accomplish that homework,
you mean that I play, I create a playbook,
something like that, for SA team,
but how I start,
I start with Radhika or you know, yeah,
so I would say the homework is more to
look at what is on the platform today.
all the apps that have been onboarded so
far and just understand the integration
that was done for it.
Like how is it integrated into the
platform?
Because each one unfortunately is a
little bit different and it's like our
standards were not documented, right?
We didn't have someone holding the pen
for this, so it has evolved over time.
It would be good to have that level set
so that when we have issues.
with a particular integration,
you would know what that is. And also,
if you know you get into the conversation
with Ray, Kevin, Candi about, well, OK,
what's the next opportunity we want to
work on?
Are there things that are deficiencies on
the platform?
You have that view of where things might
be breaking.
Or,
or inefficient or operationally
inefficient, right?
Okay, where was I?
Getting a real itchy nose in here.
The most contact pass, contact pass date.
Okay, so we get into, I guess,
from an experience cohesion perspective,
we would be talking about, like, again,
session continuity,
because it impacts the user experience,
context passing.
I would say that there is a minimum set
that we want to at least address,
and this is where typically you would
maybe want a designer to come in or like
a
team who understands AODA requirements to
come in and validate the existence of it,
because these are, I believe,
regulatory requirements.
So the ability to offer things in both
English and French,
it's not specifically an integration
implementation task.
It's more of a verification activity.
And also to meet minimum accessibility
requirements,
we have to uphold that as well.
And so the localization and accessibility
is a minimum. But it's,
I list it here because I need to put it
somewhere.
It's not like something you physically
need to do, right?
You just need to make sure that there's
compliance from the app that's coming in
and not you specifically, I would.
I mean, Owen typically does this.
So somebody just needs to ask that
question.
UX integration.
really minimal again, right?
Because we said this is something that
really we're just controlling the access
from Compass.
And so apart from making sure it lands in
the right place in the navigation,
whether it navigates to an embedded
experience, we're not talking about that.
It can go somewhere else, right?
It can open a new tab,
open a new window for all we care,
because that's not.
the objective of a tier 1 integration,
the objective is harmonizing access,
right?
So what we would do is make sure that the
user knows how to get access to it
somehow. And it can, you know,
you can go into as once once you direct
the user to that app,
the app can do its own thing.
It can be it can be a really big app
where it has its own navigation,
like a full PM system.
Like we don't care about that at all.
We're not trying to.
to we're not trying to normalize that
into Compass. The app does its own thing.
It's standalone at that stage.
You're just sending the user to the app,
right? So what words to say, no,
you want the UX integration at a tier one.
How you deploy the module is really just
a deep link with the SSO, right?
And then the ability to launch it from
Compass.
And then notifications is as required
because we're still in the middle of
building a notification service. Anyway,
it's probably not going to be available
for apps to consume,
new features to consume until it's online,
probably maybe end of Q1. So,
and then it's at the discretion of.
That this discretion of the of the
product managers,
if if it's if it's something that's
actually relevant for that particular
feature,
not everything needs to send
notifications out. Same same idea here,
this this I put in here,
we actually don't do this today,
we we we get kind of ad hoc reporting on
usage.
But...
If there's an opportunity to have that
negotiated as part of an app integration,
I would get usage metrics from from from
the from the target app,
so we we kind of bring it here,
but not not necessarily require card
requirement either,
but I think this is probably the most
important part is just being able to
audit.
access from the from the target app.
Again,
not at not at firm integration
requirements,
more like show me you can do this and
show me how we're going to be able to get
stuff back so that we can reconcile when
audit comes around and says who has
access to this stuff.
From from billing perspective,
are we go are we going to charge the firm
based on the usage of per user or it's
going to be?
I don't know how the billing takes place,
but I want to understand that.
Based on the billing, these models work,
or it's just because, for example,
here the difference between this tier and
non-integration mode is that the user
navigates and redirects to the to the URL.
Of the third-party application,
and then over there,
we just know that the user has basically,
yeah, so we know the user has accessed,
yeah, yeah.
In this model, we know that, yes,
we know that the user is using and
consuming this application,
but we know that which features with
which functions you manage,
control process, whatever.
We know this extra information. Does this.
..
provide a layer for better billing or no,
it's just as a matter of the integration.
It's not going to affect the billing.
Do you want to take that question since
you're here? Yeah,
I think the challenge is depending on who
we're talking about, the billing.
Very different, I think.
I don't think this really helps the
building billing, I should say. Like,
for example, for generally onboarding,
we pay per package,
so we can catch that on the back end,
right? So,
if you submitted a package successfully,
we capture the data team to charge for
that. Digit is based on basis points,
so how much AUA you have on the platform.
not necessarily not user ID.
So it's kind of all over the place.
Creasus, as an example, though,
is based on user ID, not usage,
but user ID.
So that'd be a good exercise here to say,
here's all the users they access, blah,
blah, blah, you can add test.
But from a billing perspective, it really,
we take it today,
we take it from a bunch of places
depending on the platform.
So we'll help with some.
but our billing models are all over the
place depending on who we integrated with.
Okay. This is more, yeah,
this gives more of a source of truth as
who has what. And then based on that,
you give it array,
that information to Ray's team,
and then Ray's team is going to decide,
do I use that information for billing or
do I just want to use like digital
adoption, like, you know.
baseline is obviously digital adoption
and knowing who's subscribed to what,
but then Ray might do more stuff with it
or might say, actually,
we're not going to count by user,
we're going to count by some other metric.
But it's important for us to know though
who has access to what, right?
That's bottom line. We still gotta,
we still gotta retain that information.
I think the biggest benefit here is the
legislation process, right? Yeah,
that is very easy to say this person has
access to this hard stop, right?
What they're doing in there is a billing
in an audit conversation,
but at least now you can tell your users,
say, hey.
Did you know why Lee has this access?
I didn't think Ali had access to do to
take that off, right? So,
we don't do a great job of that today. OK,
yeah, billing and attestation. OK, yeah,
which is takes like quarterly, yeah,
today, today, yeah,
but I think we can probably do better
than that, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Right.
So I'm not gonna,
I don't think I wanna spend, like,
we don't have a lot of this, I guess,
and Soma is the only weird,
quirky exception.
We try to avoid this like the plague,
because it's like pseudo dependencies,
you're adding external dependencies,
but you're not getting a lot of value
from an, like, from an iframe integration.
But tier 2, we're saying, okay,
we're now bringing the app into the
platform.
We're gonna iframe it or embed it.
in some hay or some way or we're gonna
like take a single page of that app and
shove it into Compass.
Minimum requirement here then, okay,
now it needs to start behaving like an
app in Compass.
So we're saying maybe minimally do the
session synchronization and error session
error handling, right?
What if a session fails, what happens?
Gotta tell the user.
in-app, what's going on,
and gracefully fail there instead of
trying to load a page.
And often you see people don't do good
session error handling, is just playing,
and you're like, what's happening?
Is it the platform? Is it the app?
I can't tell, right? Optional stuff.
Now we get into,
do you want a discussion on all the
platform services?
that needs to be there.
Oftentimes when you do a tier one,
something like WalkMe doesn't work, right?
Because WalkMe is implemented on the core
platform itself,
not apps hosted externally and or outside.
So if you want to do like a like a like a
first time walkthrough journey or what
have you not.
You can't apply that to external apps.
If you embed the app,
now you got to start applying because
it's in the core app ecosystem.
Like you can start applying some of that
walk me,
some of those walk me capabilities on top
of the app itself. I think we do that for,
do you remember we do that Candi for Soma.
I think we do. I don't remember.
And then now, optionally,
maybe we want to start making things look
a little bit more cohesive as well,
because again,
we're embedding that app into the
platform.
And Soma actually did this optionally,
the team optionally did this,
is they actually start to restyle some of
the Soma elements to Compass. So.
So then, you know,
button orientation lists,
they all start to look kind of the same.
Titles, you know,
breadcrumbs all start to look the same.
So people are not having to relearn that
orientation in a different app,
especially if they think that it's
actually part of Compass.
I put this as optional because again,
it's cost.
Is it worth it at the end of the day?
I'm not sure if half the time it's worth
it, right? So.
You make that determination at the time
of figuring out what it is that you want
to achieve with that app integration.
But feature onboarding,
it's the same thing, right?
You're just adding another app.
I think the biggest change here is really
how do you launch that app is you launch
it into the platform, right?
So having that dependency managed at
runtime is the additional requirement
here.
And like I said,
session synchronization is the big
difference. And then UX integration,
if we're doing an iframe, right,
you might want to start making them
conform to some of our design standards.
But by and large,
as long as it kind of fits and they have
some element of responsiveness in the
iframe,
that's kind of the conversation we would
have.
with that app. Again,
that was the conversation we had with
Soma when we did the integration,
if I remember. Deployment-wise,
things start to change because this is no
longer just a deep link and a launch to a
separate tab.
It is an iframe with a token handoff in
the SSO.
So just the deployment pattern is
different. I don't think, again,
we have one example of this,
so there's no standards around it.
I think this is more again.
a technical implementation problem,
should there be a conversation about the
next iframe app,
which I'm hoping you don't need to have
that conversation because it's very
costly for not a lot of value in my view.
Old 10, old 10, old 10.
Because you shove something in and then
you resize a window and it all squish is
funny and doesn't work. Everything, yeah,
like it's just the,
you might as well just put it in a
different tab. Yeah.
Yeah, iPhone, you know,
as somehow obsolete for for a test of
application web application,
it's most usually for mobile applications,
not you know, and usually, yeah,
it's usually, I think, only you know,
for integrating.
Payments,
like a stripe or things like that,
they call it, yeah, yeah.
Okay,
but then if we do decide to go all in and
say,
this must be part of the core platform
experience and must have this particular
functionality very seamlessly in the
environment that we're in and tied to our
core modules and all that fun stuff,
then we have a conversation about a tier
3 integration, which now
is all the things that we do for all the
other integrations,
because you need the security management
centralized, right?
You need the profile definition
centralized,
you need the session centralized,
and on top of that,
now I need the app functionality, right,
also managed by the platform.
So each independent feature or function
of that app needs to be registered.
into the platform,
just like you saw with like core orders
is a really good example of that.
On top of that,
now because you're in the platform and
now you have all these apps floating
everywhere,
it needs more context from the platform,
right? So user state,
like where were you last?
What context were you in last?
Can I pass that context into the app that
needs to be enabled? Otherwise.
you know,
you'll find out soon enough that actually
I have this app here, I pull it up,
but it doesn't know what I was doing
before.
It doesn't know I'm in the context of an
account, right? Like it doesn't do that.
And you're like, well, what's the point?
Like, why did NBN put it here?
So that user state, the context passing.
Now we start to talk about those things.
And as a requirement as well,
all the actions of that app needs to be
registered so that we can independently
control who has access to it and we can
put it in places as well.
Well,
this is also where we start breaking up
the application to say, okay,
there are certain things, you know,
because the app in and of itself,
if you design it standalone,
does a certain job,
has a certain user context.
But if we're seeing that, you know,
pieces of that functionality needs to be
integrated into some of the core
functions, well,
I need to take those bits and put it into
those core functions, right?
And so I would say that thing now needs
to be exposed as a micro app so we can
put it in something in context and go
into that micro app.
So heavy, heavy implementation,
one or more resources needs to be mapped
to the feature registry at this stage,
right?
Core micro app conforms to the different
access levels that we have if it's
against the core. So if I say, hey,
this person can manage orders,
and then like, you know,
fixed income is this like other app that
we do,
and then I want to pull up the fixed
income order ticket, well,
I need to control that.
But you know, on its own,
I can't just say you get access to the
app, but let the app figure it out,
because that's the you're back to tier
one. What's what the hell is the point,
right?
So it needs to understand and align to
our access standards and the way we've
constructed the access matrix if it's
core. If it's again, non-core,
nobody cares, right?
It's just you have it or you don't. Yeah,
so that's.
more of a commentary for core micro apps
and then packaging,
actually this part is the same,
like whoever should have access to it,
you package that into the correct package.
Authentication and authorization is the
same because you're already starting from
the point of full security integration,
right? So at this point,
we're going to say you're going to adopt
our IAM solution because you're in our
ecosystem, you need to call the auth APIs.
at that stage.
We're no longer context passing because
you're in the ecosystem.
That's the biggest change.
So you'll see it's not an SSL,
it's a full IAM integration.
And then with the sessions, again,
runtime synchronization of the experience
needs to be there. Maybe additional,
like if there's,
I put firm white labeling is example,
but again,
if you're fully embedded in the ecosystem,
then all the context needs to be
inherited. Like the full, like, again,
orders works like this, right?
You have firm context,
you have white labeling.
The white labeling colors apply to that
app. If your IPC, I think the only person,
like the only friend who chose to apply
white labeling for some reason,
we lost the other seven.
But language context,
default module context,
all the context that the platform has,
because it needs to live and behave and
look exactly the same as everything else,
it needs to inherit that context, right,
when you get into that.
when you get into the application.
Same thing with UX UI.
This is where again,
we even have a conversation to say,
because chances are these things are not
purchased off the shelf.
If you're going to rip something apart,
you're basically building it.
There's no other way.
You're not going to tell a vendor to
start kind of like piecing out their ego
piecing out their app unless they have a
desire to be a platform player as well.
And then you can say, oh yeah,
maybe I'll take this widget or not.
Most of SAS solutions don't work like
that, right? It's all or nothing.
So these are typically conversations you
have with something we build or something
that Infinite builds.
Then you kind of say, okay,
if you're going to full ecosystem embed
it,
now it's time to align with the design
system and apply design standards, right?
So we're working off of that.
The design system also helps reinforce
the things that you can control and
things you don't.
So that's why there's like a,
like a kind of a double benefit of doing
that. And then we talk about, well,
what's the best way to do the actual kind
of runtime integration,
deployment integration itself?
Module federation is what the core
modules are built.
upon today, that's the standard pattern.
Doesn't always have to be module
federation, it could be something else.
Again,
it's just whatever the technical teams
can come up with that's easiest to do,
but it just still happens that we landed
on module federation today.
Uh,
which which supports the whole micro
front and architecture.
And then here,
I think these should be more mandatory
because it's core. So.
Two questions. First one is about the SLA.
I understand that, for example,
for internal applications inside National
Bank,
I think it's like the informal SLA.
I understand because enterprise,
it's like that. We talk to, we don't,
for example,
get in to sign a contract with Secret
Zone to give me this. Yeah,
I think it's fine. But in terms of...
Parties,
do you we have a because the user is
viewing the feature from the from Compass
X window and he he or she makes Compass X
accountable.
if there is a timeout, if there is a,
you know, breaking something.
So how we are going to address the SLA?
Do we have a written SLA with, you know,
with different levels with our third
parties or not?
And the second question is that between
this layer and tier one.
I want to understand how we trade up.
to go which path because we have a heavy
integration in terms of the SSO and you
know feature management.
My understanding is that here we are
after the authentication.
And saying, okay,
which features the user going to access?
We hope to redirect to that app,
and it goes to the user to the UI of that
particular app,
but here we are doing that authentication,
we are doing that SSO everything.
but also we are having a heavy
implementation of the UX into our
COPRESCOCHEF.
What metrics affects our decision to go
which paths? Good question.
So first question about SLA,
it's entirely dependent on which vendor.
You're right,
our internal kind of apps don't have
strict SLAs defined because you don't
define SLAs internally.
There's some internal bank standards,
but it is pretty inconsistent.
So it's an app by app with vendors.
It's like I think we used to not do that.
I don't know if you started doing it with
partners.
We do have it now on the MSAs on our
master service agreement.
We usually define uptime and SLAs and all
these sort of things.
Generally with anyone,
like Infinite is the biggest one in Digit
or will be second,
we try to tie ourselves to whatever we
publish for Compass, right?
So if Compass has enough time with this
and the SLA is that, or for downtime,
maybe you could follow all that sort of
stuff and make them inherit.
But that's how we hold them accountable.
But to Penny's point,
there's nothing for craziness.
There's nothing for like whatever there
is to whatever they want.
Basically. Yeah, yeah.
But the newer vendors,
the newer people that were coming in as
part of our overarching government
agreement with them,
governance agreement with them,
we put it in there with the bank
agreement,
so the national bank agreement that they
have to adhere to this.
That's why also historically we've shied
away from committing SLAs to our clients.
as a result of that. We say, hey,
operating hours is there for sure,
you know,
like you should be able to access all
your services,
but specific uptime tracking. It's very,
very recent.
I think it's Sun Life and Industrial
Alliance that has it. Yeah,
but what we call them, we call them SLOs.
So, yeah, projected.
We hope to do that and there's no
financial penalties, there's no rebate,
nothing like that.
We're saying we're trying to do this.
It's good for us, but not, not, not,
not industry standard, right? Like, it's,
you know, very much the opposite of that,
and then with the trade-off discussion,
so, like, you know,
a high level benefits and drawbacks,
obviously, is framed in that sense,
but tier 3, I think, has to be,
you have to have a whole.
host of justifications for it's not a
single metric.
Number one is a strategic decision, right?
Do you like is this thing core or not?
And does it like,
do we really want to go down that path of,
because usually this happens when you
want to,
when we want to like optimize for the two
hubs we have.
Remember we have kind of the.
the firm workspace, right,
like where everything is kind of firm
level and then you go into a client and
account and then there's things you can
do at the client and account level to
make that happen in the most seamless way
possible where you can say,
I'm in the context of the account,
I can pull up an action. Well,
you kind of need to go down this path,
right? So that's a decision point.
If we want things in the accounts module,
then that's probably.
from a, like, no, like, you know,
from a strategic decisioning perspective,
is it worth it?
Do we want to stick to our strategy or
not? That's the first decision point.
Quantifiable metrics, you can tell by now,
we're not very good at it.
We just kind of like gut check and say,
does this make sense or not?
More often than not,
how we make decisions,
this is going to take a really long time.
And is the ROI going to be there at the
end?
Also depends on like how badly are
clients complaining about this, right?
Because we do have feedback,
say for servicing,
we do get the feedback of like, why, like,
you know,
that account level initiation and context
passing, like why isn't it there?
So we know about servicing,
but servicing feasibility is a totally
different issue.
So we kind of tell them like,
it's just really hard and it's going to
cost a lot of money to do it.
But if we had it our way,
or if it's something that we've built
in-house like orders,
we know that that's something that we
want to do, right?
Because we know that clients are going to
ask,
we know that it's kind of preventing them
to be as efficient as possible.
We know that.
for some of the large brokers,
even remember that there's an advisor
kind of version of this where advisors
are typically in clients and accounts,
right?
And then your head office folks are
typically not in that context.
And if we were to adequately service both,
well,
you need to put some stuff that's in
context of the account in there,
which the core of it is like
transactional stuff like servicing and.
in account management and trading.
Right, so that's,
this is why typically like tier 3 is,
it's the core of the core that you want
to invest in for that.
And even then there's a feasibility
discussion of can we do it and how much
is it going to cost for us to do it?
And then is it,
is it worth it to kind of resolve like
the client frictions that we see?
on the experience.
Like a lot of our complaints is not
really around this though.
Like we say people talk about it,
but the more overarching complaints is
lack of functionality typically when it
comes to our core apps.
It's like this thing can't do that.
Or why can't this thing do this?
Why does this thing have this rule?
Why doesn't it validate that? So.
The problems are typically within the
product itself and rarely is it does it
go into the integration territory.
That's why a lot of our stuff is tier one.
It's like, gosh, you know,
people are not complaining. Yeah.
OK. Thank you.
I think that's all I wanted to go through
for an introduction to app integrations.
You feel like something's missing here?
Like I said,
like I think you want to understand kind
of like that trade-off discussion,
by the way, goes all the way to like,
do you even do an app integration or do
you do an API integration?
So that's a decision point as well,
depending on how does it make sense?
Is it easy enough to do?
Is it better that we add an action?
which is like a button somewhere in an
app in a UI and then that actually calls
something outside and it's not an app,
it's a,
you're calling the transactional API for
it. Like that's,
that could be a decision point as well.
It's not a application tier, but. Yeah,
I understand. You know,
because from platform strategy, I want to.
understand how to make decisions better.
For example, I think...
Trading, as you said, it was from scratch.
Okay, it was,
but embedding training inside
COPRESCOCHEF.
I'm not saying it's an integration like
this, because we built it from scratch.
But it is actually hosted as a tier 3
integration.
It is module federation though, right?
So trading is actually a separate project.
It's a separate project.
App,
you can technically plug in another
INITIUM model and it will still work,
yeah, yeah, yeah, that's what I, yeah,
I want to, I want to, you know, sync with,
for example,
with whoever that I'm speaking with in
future, I want to, you know,
to have a kind of...
Help them to navigate them through, yeah,
you know, one of the trade-offs, yeah,
yeah, for sure, and you know,
mostly make it obsolete,
it's something you know,
help them to not only.
They get the better decision,
but also help our internal teams in terms
of working more efficient and yeah,
have a better consistent strategy in
long-term and mid-term. So,
I think I think so,
I think we'll double down on the exercise
to assess all the current integrations,
and once I think once you have that
documented.
we can go through a session on what
trade-offs that we have to make and how
do we make them.
I think that would be good. Just to,
because this is very conceptual,
then you'll see the thing in real deal
and there's like little,
little decision points everywhere along
the way. And then we can say, well,
why did we, you know,
cut like GICs in a certain way?
Why is it only managed?
Why doesn't have a view?
Like you'll kind of see those trade-offs
if you're looking at.
real examples. So let's, we can make that,
we can make that whatever session agenda
on the next one that's I think free,
which is next Thursday, next Tuesday.
Okay.
So, we'll connect you within Candi.
Maybe we can help Ali connect with the
right teams to understand the
implementation,
the integration implementation itself for
all the apps. Yeah, probably. Yeah,
Esther. Okay, I need to contact her. Okay.
No, that was it.
Questions for you. Very clear. Okay.
I'm glad it was not clear for us. Well,
for a long time. The package and resource,
I went into the conference pages and I
could track down what's needed for the
options, so it's very helpful. Okay.
Cool, thank you. Okay,
so we're now going to, so that's, I think,
high level discussion wise,
we went through, I'm trying to think,
we went through kind of high level
business contexts of how our firms are
set up and from organization,
and then the implement,
like in the connecting kind of like the
apps that they need.
with their setups, then we talk about,
well, how do we even bring apps on board?
That's platform integrations.
So I feel like hopefully, Ali,
that's the kind of high level concepts
out of the way.
Then I want to spend the next few
sessions getting into the actual
capabilities we have and where we are
with them.
Because there's problems with each of
them, but there's...
benefits with each of them. It's working,
but maybe it's not working as well in
some ways and against the way we
envisioned.
So I thought we could spend some time
here. Yeah,
it was part of this agenda this today to
talk about each capability one by one.
Yeah, this is where, yeah,
this is where Kenya,
I'm going to need your help.
and then talk next meeting talking about
multi-firm. Yeah, I think if we don't get,
so my plan is if we don't get to
multi-firm because we're still spending
time here,
I'd rather spend the time with you here
because it's a lot of like current
context that I have and Candi has that we
want to draw. Multi-firm, Ray knows about,
Kevin knows about,
like I think you're in good hands if we
don't finish the.
the requirements deep dive,
you'll have guidance from them because
it's a topic that we,
everybody's pretty familiar with.
But here,
like Kevin and Marie are not going to
know this,
so we'll go through the current state.
So I don't know, between you two,
is it valuable for me to stay? No. Okay.
Thank you very much.
It's good.
Yeah, because I got a meeting at 11,
have to leave that way, so...
OK,
are you are you going to the lunch today?
I think I have to want to. Are you?
I'm not like I'm in this weird like place
in transition.
I think maybe maybe I'll go with stands
like you got standing action from my team.
Richard Johnson.
All right.
Is this, I'm still sharing,
I'm still recording. Great.
Yes, well, depends on what it is.
What do you got? Peanut butter?
Are you gonna share it?
In one of the office I work in,
some guy is severely allergic to peanuts.
Ohh yeah, yeah,
so the sudden notice saying no peanut
butter in the whole office.